Bethany Simmonds

Avon, CT bsimmonds28@gmail.com (860) 671-9267

GitHub: https://github.com/bsimmonds28

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/bethany-simmonds-28-/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a B.S. in Psychology from Haverford College and six years in the nonprofit industry, including five years in marketing and communications. I started my career as an AmeriCorps Vista and now direct two departments at a national nonprofit. My strong work-ethic, project management skills, attention to detail, and creative problem-solving along with my drive to keep learning best practices have helped me successfully navigate new projects and roles. I am ready to use the skills I've honed in a new way and am completing the University of Connecticut's Coding Bootcamp in order to transition to the role of Software Engineer.

PROJECTS

Scorecard App | https://sam-scorecard-app.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/sampaul10/scorecard-app

- Summary: An application for golfers to record their hole-by-hole scores as their round progresses, review past scorecards and notes, and view a chart of past score data.
- Role: Co-Author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bulma, Chart.js, express, express-session, express-handlebars, MySQL2, Sequelize, dotenv package, bcrypt package

WeatherApp | https://bsimmonds28.github.io/weather-forecast/

- Summary: Weather app that provides current and future weather forecasts in cities.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Day.js, API, Google Fonts

Déjà Brew | <u>https://github.com/TioMeko/deja-brew</u> | <u>https://tiomeko.github.io/deja-brew/</u>

- Summary: Deja Brew is a handy application that allows users to search for breweries in local cities or anywhere in the United States.
- Role: Co-Author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API, Leaflet, Tailwind CSS, Flowbite, Wickedblocks, Google Fonts

EXPERIENCE

Food Rescue US, Remote

Director, Marketing & Grants

Marketing & Development Manager

Marketing & Development Associate

January 2022 - Present

January 2021 - January 2022

March 2020 - January 2021

- Oversee the grants and marketing departments: lead major marketing projects, the grant and marketing teams, and grant writing/management.
 - Raised \$1 million in grants in 2022, the most raised in a single year through grants for the organization since its founding.
 - Worked with local foundations, government, and major donors: Steven & Alexandra Cohen Foundation, Capital One, USA Today, Whole Foods, Lochkeed Martin, StartSmall,

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, Express, Adobe Suite, Canva, Salesforce, Wordpress

SKILLS

Creative problem-solver
Strong interpersonal skills
Experienced leader
Highly organized
Self-driven
Multi-tasker
Project management skills

EDUCATION

University of Connecticut School of Engineering, Coding Certificate, 2022-2023, Storrs, CT

24-Week Full Stack Web Development Course

Certificate to be received in May 2023

Haverford College, Bachelor of Science, Psychology, 2012-2016, Haverford, PA

Senior Thesis: The Influences of Extraversion and the Implicit Theories on Classroom Participation and the Adjustment to College Life

Varsity Squash / Squash Captain in 2016

Westover School, High School Diploma, 2008-2012, Middlebury, CT

REFERENCES

Jennifer Guhl

Connection: Coworker Title: Director of Strategic Partnerships & Major Donors, Food Rescue US General Motors, Kroger, Google Ads, etc.

- Launched a national newsletter in 2021 that goes to 26,700+ contacts and increased the open rate from 23% to 50% (According to Mailchimp, the average email open rate for nonprofits is 25.17%.).
- Initiated social media advertisements that averaged \$0.25 per link click (the 2021 nonprofit average was \$0.43).
- Doubled Instagram followers, manager influencer collaborations, and oversaw creation of Instagram reels that received up to 58K views.
- Helped design a new website and managed the website over the last two years, including continuing to build it out and update it.
- Implemented the branding guidelines and standardized accounts and marketing materials for the organization.

Eisner Health, Los Angeles, CA

Development & Volunteer Manager Volunteer & Communications Coordinator AmeriCorps Vista Volunteer Coordinator August 2019 - February 2020 April 2018 - August 2019 April 2017 - April 2018

- Established and managed the first-ever volunteer program: created policy and procedures with Human Resources, recruited and on-boarded volunteers, developed volunteer positions, supervised volunteers, and maintained the program.
- Oversaw organization's communications (including creating and scheduling television content across all sites, social media increased Instagram followers by 500% in the first 12 months, and wrote monthly CEO update emails), designed/proofed agency collateral using the Adobe Suite and Canva, managed patient events from planning to execution (including establishing the first-ever Winter Festival for 1,000+ patients and implementing census 2020 preparations and outreach).
- Supported the Director of Development by assisting with donor projects including the agency's annual luncheon/gala, database maintenance, and creating social media campaigns to engage donors.
- Project Manager for the Meaningful Use Incentive Program which brings in nearly half a million dollars per year. Achieved a 19% increase in the number of passing providers which is the equivalent of an additional \$76,500 per year.
 - Analyzed data, sent weekly update emails and reports, held bi-weekly meetings to discuss progress and updates, adjusted department workflows and communicated with department supervisors across 5 locations as well as with the Chief Medical Officer to meet goals on time.

iguhl524@gmail.com

Emily Bush

Connection: Previous Supervisor

Title: Corporate and Foundation Relations Officer, Providence Saint Joseph Health

Contact info available on request.

Andrew Signey

Connection: Previous Coworker Title: Vice President, General Services and Government Affairs, Eisner Health Contact info available on

request.